

LEANDER PAUL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT ME AT

- London, UK
- leanderpaul97@gmail.com
- +44 77690 52475
- in linkedin.com/in/leander-paul
- github.com/leanderpaul
- leanderpaul.github.io

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- NodeJS
- JavaScript
- React
- Docker
- Angular
- Bash
- MongoDB
- AWS
- SQL
- REST APIs
- Java
- GraphQL
- Rust

CERTIFICATIONS

- M001: MongoDB Basics
- M103: Basic Cluster Administration
- M220JS: MongoDB for JavaScript Developers

INTERESTS

- Coding
- Reading Novels
- Listening Music

PERSONAL PROFILE

A Software Developer with 4 years experience in web development, API design, caching and database management. Enthusiastic developer with the skill to get the job done both as a team and as a individual. Proficient in writing and testing codes, trouble shooting simple or complex problems and experienced google prompter

WORK EXPERIENCE

Part time NodeJS Developer in World Television (03/2023 to 09/2023)

- API Development for micro service architecture using RabbitMQ
- Developed REST logic and tests to validate the working of the application

Member Technical Staff in Zoho (01/2020 to 08/2022)

- API Development using XML for internal service teams
- Maintained Redis Cache in Accounts for all API queries

Full Stack Web Developer in PhospheneAI (04/2018 to 01/2020)

- Maintained positive work ethic and commitment to providing excellent service
- Designed the API and Database design for the application
- Developed the back-end server using Express, NodeJS and MongoDB
- Deployed the application to AWS and setup the internal VPC networking routes and SSL certificates

EDUCATION HISTORY

Queen Mary University of London, UK Master in Computer Science, 2022 - 2023

Anna University, India Bachelor of Technology, 2016 - 2020

PROJECTS

- Shadow Chronicle Micro service to manage expenses created using Angular framework
- Shadow Accounts Micro service to handle authentication and authorization for all other services created using Astro framework
- Shadow Archive NodeJS application to manage all the server related operations required by all the other micro services accessible by GraphQL endpoints
- Shadow Deploy Linux system service to manage CI/CD for application deployed in AWS cloud using Rust
- Setup AWS architecture to deploy application to production using VPC, EC2, S3 and SQS
- 2048 Puzzle game using NodeJS, React and Electron
- Library Management System to insert large number of books using stream API and to query those books